Curriculum vitae

MACIEJ WOJCIECHOWSKI

SENIOR SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

Mobile: +48 607 568 735

Email: maciej.wojciechowski@gmail.com

City: Gdynia, Poland

PROFILE SUMMARY

Testing expert with thirteen years of professional experience in the area of software testing and quality assurance. Specialist in planning, implementing and executing functional tests with experience in Telco, Insurance and Investment Banking domains. Currently working on Forex Derivatives project for a leading investment bank from Switzerland.

SKILLS

- Requirement analysis, Test Case design, Test estimation
- Functional testing, Exploratory testing, Usability testing
- Scrum
- Jira (with Xray plugin for test case management)
- basic Java (with some Maven, Junit, AssertJ, RestAssured)
- basic Selenium Webdriver
- basic Git, Unix, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Test Engineer

EPAM Systems, Gdańsk 10.2014 - present

Summary: manual and automated testing of web and desktop applications supporting derivatives trading on Forex market.

Responsibilities:

- key tester in multiple Scrum teams (frontend Flex, frontend HTML5, backend Java, FIX API)
- analyse and review project documentation
- provide testing estimates
- create and execute functional test cases
- create and execute regression scripts
- create and execute smoke tests
- analyse, report and manage defects
- create and run automated test scripts in Java + Selenium
- coach new team members

Test Engineer

FINEOS Polska, Gdańsk 01.2013 - 10.2014

Summary: perform testing of Fineos Claims web application (claims management in insurance and health care) as a vendor before releasing for client's UAT testing.

Responsibilities:

- analyse and review project documentation
- provide testing estimates
- draft and execute functional test cases
- draft and execute regression scripts
- draft and execute smoke tests
- analyse, report and manage defects
- create quality documentation to support QA process
- coach new team members

Curriculum vitae

IT Consultant

CGI Polska, Warsaw 08.2008 - 11.2012

Summary: perform testing of web and desktop applications supporting different Telco areas like CRM, mediation, rating, billing, interconnect, customer care.

Responsibilities:

- analyse business requirements and Dev documentation
- create test cases and detailed test plans
- plan and coordinate test activities
- write and execute test cases
- report and manage defects
- cooperate with project participants (project manager, developers, business analysts, end users)
- prepare and lead test strategy and functionality review meetings
- prepare test environments and test data
- coach new team members
- create new products for postpaid billing system running live on production
- support and coach business users in technical aspects of creation of new products (tariffs, pricing plans, promotions, discounts)

Test Engineer

LG Electronics Polska, Warsaw 11.2005 - 08.2008

Summary: assure quality for mobile devices delivered for European markets

Responsibilities:

- test core phone functionalities plus operator specific customization
- raise and manage defects
- create and update test checklists for newly implemented functionalities
- cooperate with European and Korean R&D centres
- support engineers/technical managers in local offices across Europe

EDUCATION

Poznań University of Technology, Poland

2000-2005

Institute of Electronics and Telecommunications MSc in Electronics and Telecommunications

LANGUAGES

- Polish native
- English advanced

TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATES

- Java DevQA by infoShare Academy, Gdańsk, May December 2018
- Python basic by infoShare Academy, Gdańsk, September 2017
- ISTQB Certified Tester, Foundation Level, Warsaw, November 2010
- TOEIC (Test of English for International Communication), Poznań, December 2002

HOBBIES

- Fantasy literature,
- building Lego bricks with my son